<!DOCTYPE html>
<html><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Web Programming - Zakhov's Domain</title><description>Where Insanity Meets Fun</description><link>https://zakhov.com/</link><generator>Ghost 0.8</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 15:23:19 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zakhov.com/tag/web-programming/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>WEB DEVELOPMENT’S EVOLUTION</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Just read another interesting article that I thought should be shared here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://http://www.huffingtonpost.com/himanshu-sareen/web-development-will-evolve_b_4537747.html"&gt;Huffington Post - Web Development Will Evolve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know the drill now, smartphones are becoming more and more mainstream and the number of users viewing or making use of online systems on mobile is ever increasing. The&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://zakhov.com/web-developments-evolution/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">687c3e29-806e-4b9c-a880-372c939a2728</guid><category>Web Programming</category><dc:creator>Zaki Hanafiah</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 10:05:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://zakhov.com/content/images/2016/06/www.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://zakhov.com/content/images/2016/06/www.png" alt="WEB DEVELOPMENT’S EVOLUTION"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just read another interesting article that I thought should be shared here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://http://www.huffingtonpost.com/himanshu-sareen/web-development-will-evolve_b_4537747.html"&gt;Huffington Post - Web Development Will Evolve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know the drill now, smartphones are becoming more and more mainstream and the number of users viewing or making use of online systems on mobile is ever increasing. The article does make a good point about this being the Post-PC generation. Although the semantics of the title could be debatable there is a deeper meaning to it. As more and more web designers or those involved in web development get their heads around designing primarily mobile driven websites, the main devices used to quickly surf the web will be tablets and phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, making use of stuff like the Responsive Web Design (RWD) is good for us website builders as we get to expand our target viewers to different platforms and devices. I also expect that we’ll see less use of plugins like Flash and Java runtimes in the future. As developers would be able to transition into using HTML5 features that works out of the box in modern browsers. I’m sure you know that Youtube has done this with a large archive of their videos, moving from flvs to H.264 video codec and the WebM format for HTML5 delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that is understated, especially in this country, is UAT or QA site testing. Personally, I’ve never had the opportunity to embark in a large project where user load on the site is paramount, so I can only state my personal experience as a user and through reading similar cases. If you’ve followed the Healthcare.gov debacle in the US, you won’t be surprised to hear that the same issue has been plaguing our local sites for ages now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal experience with sites like mohe.gov.my ( 10 years ago when I was applying for Uni ) and the current hot topic of the PBS( School-Based Assessment ). The PBS system was widely maligned nationwide by teachers (including my mother who is a teacher), issues like bandwidth outage and confusion on how to use the system (based on their manuals). It worsen to the point that the Director of Education had to put a halt to the system. Long story short, QA is important for Go-Live and heavy user traffic type sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note to self, consider all the above for future developments. 😉&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>EXPECTED WEB DESIGNS IN 2014</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Just finished going through an article at thenextweb.com about designs we’ll expect to see next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/dd/2013/12/29/10-web-design-trends-can-expect-see-2014/3/"&gt;TheNextWeb: Web Designs Trends Can Expect to See in 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of things I’ve already expected. The Flat UI design is gaining steam with it being heavily featured in Microsoft’&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://zakhov.com/expected-web-designs-in-2014/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">b72cb6e8-1638-4fdb-858f-ec32443614f1</guid><category>Web Programming</category><dc:creator>Zaki Hanafiah</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 10:26:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://zakhov.com/content/images/2016/06/web-design.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://zakhov.com/content/images/2016/06/web-design.png" alt="EXPECTED WEB DESIGNS IN 2014"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just finished going through an article at thenextweb.com about designs we’ll expect to see next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/dd/2013/12/29/10-web-design-trends-can-expect-see-2014/3/"&gt;TheNextWeb: Web Designs Trends Can Expect to See in 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of things I’ve already expected. The Flat UI design is gaining steam with it being heavily featured in Microsoft’s Metro UI. Metro is much maligned in the desktop pc region but from my experience, I like the tile design that they used to display information panels on the Windows Phone. My mom uses the Lumia 620 (which was recommended by me) and the design works well with navigation. I think the best compliment the flat UI can get is that Apple’s designer Jony Ive has used it as a theme for his icon design. Basically removing all the emboss and bevel elements on the icons. Heck, it’s even used by FIFA 14 for the menu interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I expect to gain steam is responsive design, a lot of websites have been catching up in terms of making their designs responsive. Of course, most of our local sites in Malaysia are still lagging but it’s nice to see that responsive design becoming a standard rather than a trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The growth of mobile phones as one of the primary quick “go-to” IT device or gadget is going from strength to strength. I would expect that there will be more applications coming out as the established organizations or companies make use of the current large user base on mobile. It’s never to late to learn, and I hope that my personal knowledge base continues to progress positively in developing on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typography is usually one of my last things to consider in web design(because a bulk of my clients either don’t care or they have their own preference). But going through the article just now I do agree that the use of san-serif fonts are getting stale and repetitive. That’s something to consider when I go for my next web design. Another thing is simplicity, colors will need to be minimized and that trend will continue throughout next year with more sites adopting a “Hero” areas. I’m not sure whether sliders will be phased out in the near time, it’s still a relevant and useful way to convey information in quick succession. I assume that on E-Commerce sites the slider trend will continue but maybe perhaps on corporate and personal sites it will be toned down. But I do positively think that sliders on mobile or small screens, especially the responsive ones don’t quite work as well as scrolling down through hero areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a couple of things to consider for next year, it never hurts to stay in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>DEEPER UNDERSTANDING OF MAGENTO AND ZEND</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently stumbled across an article on the web regarding Magento and the supposed relation it has with Zend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.webguys.de/magento/tuerchen-16-magento-is-not-zend-framework/"&gt;WebGuys: Magento is not a Zend Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author of the article mentioned that he was asked in a job interview “What do you know about Magento?” and he answered “Magento&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://zakhov.com/deeper-understanding-of-magento-and-zend/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">2971915e-e3d8-48a0-b804-e1f87ed820d1</guid><category>Web Programming</category><dc:creator>Zaki Hanafiah</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 10:27:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://zakhov.com/content/images/2016/06/zendgento.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="https://zakhov.com/content/images/2016/06/zendgento.png" alt="DEEPER UNDERSTANDING OF MAGENTO AND ZEND"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently stumbled across an article on the web regarding Magento and the supposed relation it has with Zend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.webguys.de/magento/tuerchen-16-magento-is-not-zend-framework/"&gt;WebGuys: Magento is not a Zend Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author of the article mentioned that he was asked in a job interview “What do you know about Magento?” and he answered “Magento is an open source e-commerce platform based on Zend Framework.” Wrong answer, he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading, it made me think, I’m not well versed with Zend as of now. But based on what I read on Magento’s portal it explains that “Magento is a content management system(CMS)  based on PHP and mySQL for web hosting service, which was built using parts of the Zend Framework“.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit I probably would’ve given the same answer(or maybe another deviation that I usually cook up) and end up red faced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take note from now on, Zend Framework is basically a library of classes which enables developers to create high load applications. Although structure-wise similar to Zend, Magento is a complete application that consists of a great number of strongly interconnected core extensions. Read the article linked above for a more in-depth explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to sum it up, Magento is not a Zend application, but it was built using Zend Framework components. Of course, if you’re familiar with one or the other it doesn’t hurt to know this small yet important tidbit.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss></html>